Finding Aid for School of Nursing (University of Michigan) records, 1891-2010
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Dean Ada Sue Hinshaw
  - Topical Files, 1991-1999
    - 1991-1999
      - Call to action/Suzanne Gordon, 1997 (Box 78)
      - Center for Health Services Research, 1997 (Box 78)
      - Centers of Excellence, 1995 (Box 79)
        - General, 3 folders (Box 79)
        - Scientific Review Committee (Box 79)
      - Chief Marshal, 1998 (Box 79)
      - Child care/dependence policies, 1992-1997 (Box 79)
      - China
        - Chinese Medical Association (Box 79)
        - Beijing Medical University, 1995-1998; 4 folders (Box 79)
      - Minimum class size policy, 1990 (Box 79)
      - Clinical ladder, 1995-1998 (Box 79)
      - Clinical site development task force, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Collaborations
        - General, 1996-1997 (Box 79)
        - Africa collaboration, 1994-1995 (Box 79)
        - Beijing collaboration, Johnson & Johnson, May 25-June 25, 1997 (Box 79)
        - Ford, 1997 (Box 79)
        - Nursing-Internal Medicine collaborative project, 1996 (Box 79)
      - Commitments, 1998 (Box 79)
      - Community Family Health Center
        - General, 1994-1996; 3 folders (Box 79)
        - General, 1996-1998; 3 folders (Box 80)
        - CFHC advising meeting, 1998 (Box 80)
        - CFHC articles, 1996-1997 (Box 80)
        - CFHC: an interdisciplinary model, 1996 (Box 80)
        - Clinical-Director position, CFHC, 1996 (Box 80)
        - Grants, CFHC, 1996-1999 (Box 80)
        - Huron Valley Child Guidance Clinic, 1999 (Box 80)
        - Nursing Centers Task Force, 1995-1998 (Box 80)
        - Planning (Box 80)
        - Task force (Box 80)
      - Congratulatory, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 80)
      - Cook Institute, 1996-1997 (Box 80)
      - Correspondence, 1994-1998; 5 folders (Box 81)
      - Cost report, 1993-1994 (Box 81)
      - Course information, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Database, 1994-95, 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Dalian, Patrick (Senator Inouye's Office), 1994-1997; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Department of Army, 1997 (Box 81)
      - Department of Navy, 1995 (Box 81)
      - Director of Undergraduate and Special Programs, 1994 (Box 81)
      - Division Directors Meeting, 1998 (Box 81)
      - Educational Services for Nursing, 1996 (Box 81)
      - Elected individuals, 1998 (Box 81)
      - Endowed Chair, 1996-1998; 2 folders (Box 81)
      - Endowment Accounts, 1995-1999 (Box 81)
      - Enrollment, 1992-1999; 6 folders (Box 81)
      - FT's, 1996-1999; 3 folders (Box 81)
      - Faculty
        - Affiliate faculty policy (Box 81)
        - Faculty, aging, 1999 (Box 81)
        - Congratulatory letters, 2002 (Box 81)
        - Faculty meetings
          - 1995 (Box 81)
          - 1997-1998 (Box 81)
        - Faculty nurse practitioner program, 1994-1997 (Box 81)
        - Faculty Practice Plan Advisory Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 81)
        - Faculty productivity, 1994-1997 (Box 82)
        - Faculty retreats
          - 1988 (Box 82)
          - 1992 (Box 82)
          - 1996 (Box 82)
          - 1997 (Box 82)
          - 1998 (Box 82)
        - Faculty--vision, thoughts, issues, 1994-1997 (Box 82)
      - Family Nurse Practitioner (Box 82)
      - Ferndale Laboratories, 1995-1996 (Box 82)
      - Foundations, 1994 (Box 82)
      - Governing Faculty, 1997 (Box 82)
      - Graduate Medical Education, 1996-1998; 2 folders (Box 82)
      - Graduate PhD program syllabus, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Grants
        - Annenburg Grant w/social work, 1996 (Box 82)
        - Faculty development fund teaching grants, 1997-1998; 2003 (Box 82)
        - Family Nurse Practitioner Program, 1995 (Box 82)
        - Fuld Grant, 1998 (Box 82)
        - Grant preparation, 1998 (Box 82)
        - Grant submissions, 1994-1997 (Box 82)
        - P. Kalisch NYC program, 1995 (Box 82)
        - Medicaid, GME RFP, 1997; 3 folders (Box 82)
        - Mock review of an interactive research proposal, 1996 (Box 82)
        - Pontiac Community Initiatives, 1994-1995 (Box 82)
        - Professional Nurse Traineeship Program, 1998-1999 (Box 82)
        - PUMA project--Barbara Guthrie, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Guidelines for Committee and Task Force Chairships, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Handbook of clinical nursing research, 1994 (Box 82)
      - Health leader, 1993 (Box 82)
      - Hearth-Ameritech initiative, 1994-1996 (Box 82)
      - Human genetics, 1996 (Box 82)
      - Human subjects review committee, 1995-1997 (Box 82)
      - Hurley Medical Center, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Huron Valley Visiting Nurses, 1998 (Box 82)
      - Indirect costs, 1995 (Box 82)
      - Information systems projects, 1995-1996 (Box 82)
      - Journal of Nursing management, 1994 (Box 82)
      - LAN project, 1994-1995 (Box 83)
      - LAN user support group, 1995 (Box 83)
      - Limited reorganization, 1995 (Box 83)
      - Literature Group, 1995 (Box 83)
      - Long distance learning, 1995-1996 (Box 83)
      - Managed care, 1995 (Box 83)
      - Management of healthcare technology, 1998 (Box 83)
      - Master's degree program, 1994 (Box 83)
      - Generic master's degree in nursing, 1998 (Box 83)
      - Master of Science in Anesthesia program, UM-Flint (Box 83)
      - Master's degree at Northwest Michigan College, 1994 (Box 83)
      - Michigan Consortium: University based nurse managed primary care (resubmission of grant), 1997 (Box 83)
      - Mission statement, 1983-2001; 2 folders (Box 83)
      - Moore II resolutions, 1997-1998
        - General, 1997-1998; 2 folders (Box 83)
        - Mutual gains [goes with Moore II], 1997-1998 (Box 83)
      - Neuroscience, 1994 (Box 83)
      - New academic programs policy, 1994 (Box 83)
      - Neurobehavior training program, 1995; 2005 (Box 83)
      - New Century Fund, 1997 (Box 83)
      - Nurse midwives
        - General (Box 83)
        - Nurse-midwifery summit, 1994 (Box 83)
        - American College of Nurse-Midwives Accreditation self evaluation report, 1992; 2 volumes (Box 83)
        - American College of Nurse-Midwives, accreditation self-evaluation report, 1997 (Box 83)
        - Nurse-midwifery service/practice directors third annual institute, 1998 (Box 83)
      - Nurse practitioner, 1995-1996 (Box 83)
      - Nursing-health web homepage, 1996 (Box 83)
      - Nursing History Society, 1995-1998 (Box 83)
      - Nursing programs (Box 84)
        - Program reviews (schools), 1994 (Box 84)
        - Stats on nursing programs, 1994-1996 (Box 84)
        - Nursing schools, 1994-1997 (Box 84)
        - University of Alabama-Birmingham, Ph.D degree proposal, 1995 (Box 84)
        - University of Arizona, 1998 (Box 84)
        - Case Western Reserve -- School of Nursing President's Advisory Committee for Promotion and Tenure, 1995 (Box 84)
        - Bangladesh, 1996 (Box 84)
        - University of Detroit Mercy, Commission on the Future Task Force, 1995-1996 (Box 84)
        - Howard University, 1996-1997 (Box 84)
        - University of Iowa, external review, 1995 (Box 84)
        - University of Mary, 1995 (Box 84)
        - Oakland University, 1998-1999 (Box 84)
        - University of Washington, 1995 (Box 84)
        - Wayne State University, 1995-1998 (Box 84)
      - Nursing Systems Interest Group, 1997 (Box 84)
      - Organizations, 1994-1998 (Box 84)
      - Parke-Davis, 1994-1995 (Box 84)
      - PEW (Pew Health Professions Commission), 1994-1998; 2 folders (Box 84)
      - Pharmacy course, 1995 (Box 84)
      - Picker/Commonwealth Scholars Program, 1994-1995 (Box 84)
      - Pontiac Schools
        - Journal article Pontiac Schools, 1996 (Box 84)
        - Pontiac School System "Advance" article, 1996 (Box 84)
        - Pontiac materials relevant to news releases, 1996 (Box 84)
        - Pontiac community initiative, 1994-1997 (Box 84)
      - Postdoctoral education, 1998 (Box 84)
      - Preceptor Recognition Task Force, 1997 (Box 84)
      - Prescriptive authority
        - General, 1996-1997 (Box 84)
        - Prescriptive authority hearing, 1997 (Box 84)
        - Senate health policy committee hearing on SB1001, 1996 (Box 84)
      - Press contacts (Box 84)
      - Program reviews
        - Program reviews update, 1991-1992 (Box 84)
        - Program reviews, SN specialties & sub-specialties -- master's level (Box 84)
        - Guidelines for review of current and proposed offerings, 1991 (Box 84)
        - Process and recommendations, 1992 (Box 84)
      - Project reviews -- recommendations, 1992; 2002 (Box 84)
      - Promotions
        - General, 1997-1998 (Box 84)
        - Promotions/clinical track, 1998 (Box 84)
      - Proposals for 8 million, 1996 (Box 84)
      - Proposal support letters, 1993-1994; 3 folders (Box 85)
      - Proposed new programs, 1994 (Box 85)
      - Quality improvement team, 1995-1996 (Box 85)
      - Questionnaires, 1994-1995 (Box 85)
      - Rehabilitation Nursing Foundation, 1996 (Box 85)
      - Research America, 1998 (Box 85)
      - Research funding, 1995 (Box 85)
      - RN studies program, 1995-1996 (Box 85)
      - Research budget, 1995 (Box 85)
      - Review of the School of Nursing, 1989 (Box 85)
      - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation
        - General, 1996-1997; 3 folders (Box 85)
        - RWJ meeting, 1997 (Box 85)
        - RWJ Advisory committee meeting, 1997 (Box 85)
        - Robert Wood Johnson gerontology study, 1986 (Box 85)
        - Robert Wood Johnson/University of Detroit Mercy, 1995-1998; 3 folders (Box 85)
      - Sabbatical file, 1995-97, 2 folders (Box 86)
      - Salaries
        - Salary analysis, 1997 (Box 86)
        - Merit raises, 1998 (Box 86)
        - Staff salary merit, 2000-2002 (Box 86)
        - Faculty/staff merit raises, 1994-1997; 2 folders (Box 86)
        - Salary program, 1994-1995 (Box 86)
      - Science and policy, 1995 (Box 86)
      - Self-study report for continuing accreditation for baccalaureate and master's degree, 1993 (Box 86)
      - Shipman Scholar, 1996 (Box 86)
      - Sigma Theta Tau International
        - General, 1994-1999; 2 folders (Box 86)
        - 75th anniversary campaign's International Board of Directors, 1994-1996 (Box 86)
      - Sponsored funds report, 1996 (Box 86)
      - Staff responsibilities--various offices, 1992-1993 (Box 86)
      - Statistics (Box 86)
      - Stats camp, June 1996 (Box 86)
      - Students
        - Student confidentiality, 1998 (Box 86)
        - Student ratings, 1994 (Box 86)
        - Student review process (Box 86)
        - Students, 1979 (Box 86)
      - Symposium on traditional healing, 1996 (Box 86)
      - Systems Development Coordinator search, 1995 (Box 86)
      - Taiwan, distance hearing project, 1994 (Box 86)
      - Tenure
        - Promotion casebooks for instructional faculty, 1997-1998 (Box 86)
        - Tenure track recommendations, 1994 (Box 86)
      - Total quality management, 1996 (Box 86)
      - Transition care and points, 1996 (Box 86)
      - Travel (Box 86)
      - Traverse City, 1996 (Box 86)
      - TriService Nursing Research Group, 1994-1999 (Box 86)
      - UMHS partnership, 1996-1997 (Box 86)
      - UMMC primary care network, 1994-1995 (Box 86)
      - UMTV project, 1994 (Box 86)
      - Undergraduate
        - New undergrad admission, 1995; 2002-2003 (Box 86)
        - Undergraduate director position, 1995-1998 (Box 86)
        - Undergraduate Education Committee, 1994-1995 (Box 86)
        - Undergraduate Internet course, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Undergraduate and non-traditional programs, 1996 (Box 86)
        - Undergraduate research, 1994 (Box 86)
        - Undergraduate research opportunity program, 1995 (Box 86)
      - Unification models, 1980 (Box 86)
      - Unit assessment, 1994 (Box 86)
      - University of Michigan, 1994-1998 (Box 87)
      - Updates, 1997 (Box 87)
      - Value Centered Management (VCM)
        - General, 4 folders (Box 87)
        - Responsibility Center Management, 1994 (Box 87)
        - VCM budget file, 1996 (Box 87)
        - Special VCM folder, 1995-1996 (Box 87)
      - Violent situations, 1998 (Box 87)
      - Web-based course, 1993; 1999 (Box 87)
      - Wirthlin Worldwide, 1997 (Box 87)
      - Workshops
        - General, 1994 (Box 87)
        - Measurement workshop, 1998 (Box 87)
        - Community-based initiatives, 1994 (Box 87)
- Archived Website
  The Archived Website series (2002-2008, 1.24 GB; 2010- ) documents the academic programs, accomplishments, resources, events, and people at the School of Nursing. Content includes important news and announcements, publications such as newsletters and student handbooks, and information about admissions, curriculum, degree requirements, faculty, alumni relations, and the overall mission of the School. Also included is the website for the Rho chapter of Sigma Theta Tau International, the honor society of nursing at the University of Michigan. The series is arranged chronologically and includes content captured by the Internet Archive starting in 1999 as well as captures provided by Bentley Library archivists 2002, 2003, and 2008. Starting in 2010, this archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/.
  - School of Nursing
    - 1999-2001
      (These versions were preserved by the Internet Archive and are made available through its Wayback Machine. The Bentley Historical Library is not involved in the collection or maintenance of this material.)
    - 2001-[ONGOING]
    - May 15, 2002, .ZIP file
    - May 22, 2003, .ZIP file
    - May 12-13, 2008, .ZIP file
    - 2010-[ONGOING]
  - Related resources
    - 2010-[ONGOING]